in the framework I'm about to show you
is going to blow your mind this is a
framework that takes your python code
and generates a fully functional
interactive web application powered by
react and next JS imagine going from
having to learn JavaScript react and
next.js to instead just learning python
to use a framework that generates that
JavaScript react and xjs code for you
the name of the framework is pinecore
and I have prepared a couple of tiny
demos to show you how it works after
importing Pinecone we create a function
that is going to build our home page we
are going to build the UI using some of
the many pre-made Pinecone components we
are going to use the center component to
put things in the center we're going to
use a heading component to create a big
text that says click we're going to use
an H stack or horizontal stack to put a
button next to a text next to another
Button as you can also see we are adding
CSS Styles as well using python keyword
arguments then all we have to do is
create a Pinecone app and the page and
compile it after we save our code and
run our app from the console pinecon
will generate a next JS application that
will show us the UI we just implemented
that is already cool we are building a
react UI using only python as you can
see our app does not do anything let's
fix that by adding a state to our app
let's create a class called state which
is going to hold a counter keeping track
of the clicks and it will have two
methods that will increase or decrease
the total clicks now we can connect our
UI with the state by displaying the
number of Clicks in the state and by
telling our buttons what to do when they
are clicked and last but not least let's
connect the state with our app and go
back to our browser to a fully
interactive application so what do you
think isn't it cool to be able to
generate a next JS app using only python
code I think it is under the hood
Pinecone is doing a lot of cool things
it takes the functions we used like PC
heading and PC button turns them into
react components and then builds the
pages using next JS to make the default
components look nice python is actually
using the beautiful chakra UI Library
under the hood along with the next JS
app pinecon also generates a fast API
python server on the background and it
is on the server where the state of the
application leaves pinecon handles all
the communication between the next JS
app and the fast API server as well this
means that if you are using some python
package for API data science or whatever
you can use it on Pinecone and it will
run on a fast API bucket let's finish up
by building a dog viewer app after
importing Pinecone I also want to import
a request a pure python package after
inside of a state class I defined two
properties an image URL string and a
fetching Boolean that will tell us if we
are fetching from the API or not inside
of our state we will add two methods one
to set fetching to true and the other
one to send a request to an API that is
going to give us a random dog photo the
UI code is very easy to understand we
create a heading inside of a vertical
stack and a button which as you can see
will call the two methods in our state
when it's clicked then we use the PC con
component to display something if a
condition is met here we are saying that
only if the state fetching is true we
want to show a loading indicator and
here we are saying that if the image URL
in our state isn't empty then we want to
show the image using the PC image
component back on our browser as you can
see it all works great the loader
indicator shows up in the random login
image is shown super super cool Pinecone
is very young and we have to see what it
becomes but personally I really like the
idea and how the API feels building the
UI with pine cone feels more like
working with flutter rather than react
JS Pinecone is basically an abstraction
a layer on top of the chaos of react and
next JS it's an interface I don't think
HTML CSS JavaScript react are ever going
to be replaced but I find it really
interesting to think how maybe in the
future we are not going to be directly
writing JavaScript and react code and
instead we might use an interface like
Pinecone and less scary looking
programming languages like python to
generate that JavaScript and react.js
code I am very curious to know what you
think about pinecon so please write down
your thoughts on the comment section
below I personally like the idea and I'm
happy to know that there are people
working on how to make me more
productive as a developer but on the
other hand I think that JavaScript react
and NCAA aren't that hard to learn so
maybe we shouldn't put so much effort
into replacing them and we can just
learn them and be done with it in
talking about a learning JavaScript
react Python and next.js did you know
that you can learn them for absolutely
free click the link below right now to
enroll in any of our many free courses
we not only have JavaScript react Python
and next.js we also have redox graphql
golang Dart flutter among many others
for free click the link below and I will
see you there honor though
see you on the next one bye
foreign
[Music]